In the winter of 1634, an extraordinary man began a perilous
journey into the North American wilderness.
Black Robe is a adventure, drama, history film directed by Bruce Beresford.
Missionary Father LaForgue travels to the New World in hopes of
converting Algonquin Indians to Catholicism.
Accepted, though warily, by the Indians, LaForgue travels with the Indians using
his strict Catholic rules and ideals to try and impose his religion.
Laforgue, played by Lothaire Bluteau.
Annuka, played by Sandrine Holt.
Chomina, played by August Schellenberg.
Chomina's Wife, played by Tantoo Cardinal.
Neehatin, played by Lawrence Bayne.
Daniel, played by Aden Young.
Black Robe is a 1991 historical drama film directed by Bruce Beresford,
adapted by Brian Moore from his 1985 novel of the same name.
Set in the 17th century, it depicts the adventures of a Jesuit
missionary tasked with founding a mission in New France.
To do so, he must traverse 2,400 km of harsh wilderness with the help of a group of
Algonquins, facing danger from both the unfamiliar environment and rival tribes.
The title refers to the nickname given to the Jesuits by the
Algonquins, referring to his black cassock.
The film stars Lothaire Bluteau in the title role, with other cast members: Aden Young, Sandrine
Holt, Tantoo Cardinal, August Schellenberg, Gordon Tootoosis and Raoul Trujillo.
It was the first official co-production between a
Canadian film team and an Australian one.
It was shot mostly in the Canadian province of Quebec.
It was Young and Holt's film debut.
Black Robe premiered at the 1991 Toronto International Film Festival and was given a wide
release on 6 October, becoming the highest-grossing Canadian film of 1991.
It received generally positive reviews and won several accolades.
It was nominated for ten Genie Awards and won six, including Best Motion Picture, Best Director
(Beresford), Best Adapted Screenplay (Moore) and Best Supporting Actor (Schellenberg).
It was also nominated for ten AACTA Awards, with
Peter James winning Best Cinematography.
The film explores themes of quebec, wilderness, native
american, journey, jesuits (society of jesus).
The tone is emotional.